



# **MISSION**

Being a problem solver, and an artist at heart, I want to bring *my* creativity to solve tomorrow's problems, with elegant solutions.



## CONTACT



+1(912) 755-7989



dehinton@usc.edu



Los Angeles, California



www.deveretthinton.com



# **SKILLS**

C++ Python
PHP C#
HTML CSS
Javascript Web Design
VR gLUA
Mathematics Robotics
SAGE Game Design

Game Engines
Time Management
Project Direction
Digital Media Design
Community Leadership



# **LANGUAGE**



**English**Mother Language



**Japanese**Limited proficiency

# D. Everett Hinton

Software Engineer



# **EXPERIENCE**

### **Divinity Servers**

2014-2018

A small-server hosting startup founded by me and my partner.

- Automation of configurable Linux virtual machines.
- Command line experience with remote servers.
- Front-end and back-end development of customer experience.

#### **Undergraduate Research**

2017-2018

Mathematics research on Elliptical Curves over Finite Fields at AASU.

- Constructed primality test programs in SAGE & Python.
- Attended group conferences and presented research to peers.
- Worked with a team to examine properties of Hilbert polynomials.

#### **Freelance Programming**

2013-Present

Managing a clientele base of for-comission programming tasks.

- Technical skill to create an end-product for clients.
- Team-based feedback to produce desired result.
- Knowledge of game engines and their functions.



# **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Southern California**

2018-Present

Physics & Computer Science undergraduate student at USC.

- First generation college student.
- Research on computational solutions to the 3-body problem.
- Network operator for the school of engineering.

# **RECOGNITION & AWARDS**

#### Winner of Hack for Savannah

2017

A group hackathon for improving post-hurricane city resiliance.

#### 1st Place Winner of TechFest 2018

2018

An ACM competition for both graduate and undergraduate students.



# **STATEMENT**

Since I was a child I have had a fascination with video games; how they worked, why they existed, and how I could make one? This kick started my entrance into the world of programming. However, now a bit older, I've realized my goal is a bit more ambitious; space. Being a firm believer that humans will shortly enter space, and knowing the crop of new problems that will arise, my dream is create a OoL solutions firm that will be two steps ahead of all these issues. The future is my passion.